Divyesh Pandey

UI Designer-Lead

Contact

Address

739, Kaveri Apartment, D6, Vasant Kunj, New Delhi

Phone

+91-8826229670

Email

divyeshpandey91@gmail.com

Qualifications

Bachelor of Arts

CSJM University

Diploma in Graphics and Web designing

Arena Animation

Interests

Music Singing Travelling Hiking Sports

Skillset

Designing: UXPin, Invision, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator & Adobe InDesign.

Development: HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, JS, LESS & SCSS.

Framework: Bootstrap, Angular Material, 960Grids, Foundation

Working Skill: Wireframe design, Interactive Mockup design,

Mobile app design,

Career Summary

UI Designer with more than **7 years** of experience in IT analysis, web applications, providing requisite solutions, turning around the ideas into **design** and design into development with the help of **HTML**, **CSS** and **JS** workflow.

UI Trainer and efficient team manager helping the entire graphics department to work in planned and effective manner.

Experience

Avalon Information System | Team Lead (UI)/Trainer

June, 2016 - Present

Heading the UI department in overseeing the team of 5 designers dealing with multiple design projects. Helping client and program managers to provide the best design solutions within the stipulated timeline.

Job Profile

- Supervising the Graphics and Web design team for in all organization projects
- Guiding team in completing task and compiling the project within timeline.
- Providing solution/supervision for CMS based web applications.
- Building solutions by designing Interactive **Mock-ups & Wireframes**.
- Fast pace mock-ups conversion to HTML mark-up.
- Using **Bootstrap** & **Material** Framework for fast pace development.
- **SPA** (Single Page Application) Design & Develop to show interactive presentation with in the single page.
- Single Orientation web applications with use of **D3.js and SVG**.
- Multi device support Responsive Web Applications.
- Industry standard style guide design for generic application development.
- Designing & setup CSS Pre-Processor (LESS & SCSS) based projects.
- Creating parallax web applications using jQuery & JavaScript.
- Providing training to trainees & new team members.
- Helping developers in integrating the designs.
- Designing Mobile Application design for both IOS & Android.
- Advocating material design to provide best solution.

Nagarro Software | Sr. UI Designer

Mar, 2015 - June, 2016

Working on client side & helping with instant solution related to UX as a UI Designer.

Styleguide Building, PSD to HTML, HTML to PDF, SVG based markup design, Single Page Application design, ecommerce website design and development, CMS (WordPress) based web design and development and Parallax website design and development.

Managing Skills: Sound knowledge of Agile Methodology, Experience of handling and guiding team & Working knowledge of JIRA and Confluence.

Job Profile

- Creating mock-ups, wireframe & mark-ups of the projects.
- POCs to understand the new technology & enhance the coding skills
- Fast pace mock-ups conversion to HTML mark-up
- Framework **Bootstrap** & **Material design**-based project development.
- Mobile Friendly (Responsive Web Application) development.
- CSS Pre-Processor (LESS & SCSS) based project setup & design.
- Parallax based web application using JQuery & JavaScript.
- Training trainees & new team members.
- Helping developers in integrating the designs.

Avalon Information System | Web Designer

Apr, 2014 – Mar, 2015

Managing the graphics and web related task to provide the solution within the stipulated timeline

Job Profile

- Create Interactive Mock-ups & Wireframes.
- Converting mock-ups to HTML mark-up.
- Framework Bootstrap & Material design based project development.
- Mobile Friendly (Responsive Web Application) development.
- CSS Pre-Processor (LESS & SCSS)based project setup & design
- Design & Develop SPA (Single Page Application).
- Parallax based web application using jQuery & JavaScript.
- Helping developers to integrate the designs

Xicom Technologies | Web Designer

June, 2013 - Apr, 2014

Managing Graphics and web related tasks for the organization.

Job Profile

- Converting mock-ups to HTML mark-up.
- Framework Bootstrap & Material design based project development.
- Mobile Friendly (Responsive Web Application) development.
- CSS Pre-Processor (LESS & SCSS)based project setup & design
- Design & Develop SPA (Single Page Application).
- Parallax based web application using JQuery & JavaScript.
- Helping developers to integrate the designs.
- Converting HTMLs to PDF.

Pixel Conceptions | Web Designer

May, 2011 – Mar, 2013

Graphic Designer and HTML Developer looking after multiple projects to provide best design solutions.

Job Profile

Converting mock-ups to HTML mark-up.

- Using Bootstrap & Material Design Framework.

- Design & Develop SPA (Single Page Design).
 Single Orientation web application with use of D3.js and SVG.
 Mobile Friendly (Responsive Web Application) web applications.
 Interactive web application using JQuery.
- Helping developers to integrate the designs.